hi everybody i'm john kiriakou pan
quakes brand ambassador i want to tell
you that uh as part of our june public
delivery meeting uh we do this every
month we give you the the latest
developments in pan quake i just got the
latest update and i have to say that
there are so many new exciting features
to pan quake i almost can't wait to talk
about it uh everything from from emojis
to uh to
new colors and the structure of the of
the dashboard it's really incredible the
progress that's been made uh we're here
with susie dawson the founder of pan
quake she's going to walk us through
some of the specifics but before we get
to susie i just have to say how excited
i am about the development of pan quake
how quickly things are moving forward
and how much i think you're going to
enjoy what pan quake has to offer
there's no other social media network
out there like pan quake this is really
something special let's go over to susie
dawson
hi john thank you so much for being here
for that awesome intro
um everyone welcome to the stream really
happy to be here again with you
um june has probably been the most
prolific month we've ever had for the
pancake development team i know that
i've told you that in the last couple of
months and every month it's been true
the velocity of our build just increases
exponentially and the level of
completion of the application does as
well we are now so close to the end of
the application build that we can taste
it and we have been doing an enormous
amount of work also simultaneously on
operational planning so i'm going to
take you into my presentation for this
month
and show you what we have all been up to
so here we go we are at the one year
market now since we first began coding
pancake we are in the final phase of our
fundraising campaign we've achieved 27
of the amount that we will need in order
to launch the product so you can expect
a huge marketing push from us in the
coming months to polish that off
we are working towards delivery of our
beta our version 1.0 of the product
we are currently working really hard on
refining our network protocol which is a
key component of our blockchain and
various service integrations which i'll
talk through a bit more with you
in terms of marketing you may have may
have seen that sean o'brien and john
kiriakou have been out there doing
interviews we've got
print press coming up we've got some
amazing new youtube channels that we'll
be appearing on as well
we are still accepting beta applications
if you would like to apply to be one of
the first 5 000 users of pancake.com
you can do so at pancwake.com
5000 we will keep that application
process open right up until the release
of the beta so there is still time to
apply if you haven't already
in terms of talk liberation our privacy
and technology focus block we haven't
spent an enormous amount of time in the
last couple of months on that because
we've been
so deeply into the build of pain quick
we really didn't want to lose any time
on that
however i can tell you
that wl dragnet part 2
which is the second part of a huge
investigation that we released back in
october november last year it's about 75
complete and you can expect to see that
in the near future and
it's pretty hard hitting and i'm
expecting it's going to make some waves
so
very soon you can look out for that
okay in terms of development progress
we have had a huge month
we can now send quakes to the timeline
so we can now write messages on pan
quick we can attach files
we can schedule the quakes in advance
for an advanced date and time
we can add emojis we've got every emoji
under the sun
very soon we will have a gif library in
there as well and we can hit that send
button and we can see that message
appear in real time on our timeline
we also have got our inline compose for
replies so once that quake hits the
timeline you can now click on the reply
button a blank message template drops
down underneath and you can directly
reply to that message and then it
appears correctly in the thread
we also literally today have completed
all of the profile editing functions
that means that you can now select a
thumbnail for to be your avatar on the
application you can customize your bio
information we have got a 1 000
character biospace which is a dramatic
improvement on certain other short
messaging systems that i will shall
remain nameless so you get to tell your
story and your bio and people can swipe
up or
mouse wheel scroll to read through as
much or
or as little of it as they like
you can add a public email contact if
you want one but of course you don't
have to it's totally optional you can
perform your self-verification process
or you can add in public website
information as well if you want people
to uh go out to other links that you
have
um so that's another huge piece of work
that's been done and that's the
completion of another major panel on our
drag and drop interface um
you can also delete quakes now as well
so if you change your mind and want to
get rid of something you can do that
the search function and the search panel
is now working you can also clear your
search terms as well in one click
the
ability to accept terms of service on
sign up in our signup user flow is also
working
and pretty spectacularly we now have
the ability to have the interface
in nine different languages which is
pretty impressive for the beta so you
can expect to be able to use pan quake
in english and french and german and
spanish and portuguese and russian and
arabic and mandarin chinese and in hindi
so pretty impressive coverage for what
is just the first iteration of this
product
we also have really cool digital
animations that have been created super
cute fun
little animations in the interface
and um we also now have a bug reporting
function that we've created
where if users find any bugs or you know
with whatever your browser version or
operating system version is you can
actually report that to us and our
development team can address that
straight away which is really a critical
part of why we're doing a beta release
we want you guys to be able to be our
users our user testers and to be able to
communicate to us any changes that you
think need to be made
other major delivery achievements and
these are huge enormous pieces of work
that have been months and months and
months coming which we've made massive
progress on our stat service integration
is happening now i'm going to let sean
talk more about the stat service because
it was really his baby
but this is the service that allows us
to tally and display
follower counts following counts
number of quakes that you've quaked
accounts numbers of replies of likes of
shares of quakes that have been built
into or included into fan quakes so
really integral part of the system
really major component
and that is right now being integrated
into the application
service planning we have designed our
back-end software which our staff will
use to administrate our system
months of work has gone into that maybe
four months of work has gone into that
we're extremely happy with the quality
and the level of that design
our staff can now build that out
and we will have the systems that we
need in place to deliver and support
this application for our users as part
of that we're also doing a live chat
integration we've already been working
on the preliminary configuration for
that so the subscribed pan quick users
will be able to chat live with
pancreatic customer support
staff members so no more getting obscure
nonsensical emails five days or two
weeks after you
file a report you'll be able to have
live feedback that makes sense from
someone who really cares
in terms of operations we've also scoped
all of our hosting requirements and our
legal requirements and compliance
requirements for the first um
iteration for the beta application and
those um scopes have now been issued and
are ready for implementation and
properly scheduled as well
our
oh yes and we're actually testing this
other amazing thing that has happened is
that we already are doing our quality
assurance testing that means we are
ourselves testing the application in
multiple different environments testing
every single function and form
and
where we find bugs within logging tasks
for those issues to be resolved and we
have already performed multiple bug
fixes
so you can be sure that we're really
doing our due diligence on this in in
every respect
okay every month we talk through our
talk lab publication metrics
um having not published anything through
this last couple of months that we've
been just heads down on and tails up on
the build i'm amazed to see that we
still somehow are gaining subscribers
and that we haven't lost any you guys
are amazing to continue supporting us
what talk
liberation.substitute.com does is it
gives you a way to make a
monthly recurring donation only five
dollars a month um to the pan quake
build so every dollar coming through
talk liberation supports the pan quake
project so thank you to those who are
continuing to sign up and continuing to
support us through that channel even
though we haven't yet been publishing uh
further content that will change however
as i mentioned with the impending wl
dragon part two
um so what else is happening coming soon
very soon you can expect this
definitely in the next week
um you will get to see more of the
pancake ui in action and this will be
released first on our telegram channel
so
if you want to see that go to t dot me
slash pancake uh follow our channel and
you will get to see a super cool video
of the pancake application being used in
real time
okay so in terms of the campaign the
crowdfunder we completed phase one in
record time we completed phase two which
was um
a huge you know a huge thing to pull off
but we did it
and that is what is fun excuse me that
is what is funded the build so all this
amazing development progress that is
happening right now is because of your
support through phase two
now we must finish phase three so that
we can employ the team that will support
this product that means customer service
reps that means technical support 24 7
on the ground in iceland it means
content moderators it means account
administrators
and
together just like we did with phase one
and phase two together we're gonna pull
this off
the 500k that we need to raise is a tiny
fraction of what other businesses spend
when they're building comparable
products so pan quake staff have
delivered
record amounts of work for tiny amounts
of money and we now just need to all
pull together
push through that final phase and
pancreate will be in your hands then it
will be you sending paper sending quakes
it will be you stacking pan quakes it
will be you with your own user data
stored on your device it will be you
enjoying the privacy and the respect for
users that quake brings you every step
of the way
so thank you so so much for being here
with us i'm now going to pass over to
sean o'brien who's going to tell you a
bit more about what has been going on
from a dev perspective and around the
stat service and other cool innovations
in the meantime please reward the hard
work of the team by getting to
pancake.com donate contributing to the
completion of the campaign so that we
can get this to you faster thank you so
much hi sean
awesome thank you susie and thank you
john as well um i'm excited yet again
for another amazing month um it's just
been so much progress so quickly and
seeing the network alive which you all
will soon see yourselves um i i think
it's just been so much fun
uh but also the dev teams coming
together in like you know the way a dev
team should right um doing bug fixes and
you know testing and doing real qa even
at this point in the build um and having
that sort of continuous development
process um you know constantly improving
is really awesome so um yeah it's
amazing stuff
on the stats service you know that's a
piece we probably haven't talked very
much about um so just to recap a little
bit because we've kind of hinted at it
or talked about it in different ways
so the data you intend to be private
stays on your machine right in pan quake
um but on your machine on the app that
you're running on your device um the
data that you intend to be public that
goes in the public blockchain right so
those are your quakes your pan quakes et
cetera et cetera
but this is a living breathing social
network right it's not just some dry
spreadsheet or something so there's
interactions between users and there's
also you know um trends and there's also
you know sort of high level metrics so
like how many users are in the network
you know what's the most you know
popular pan quake who are the leaders
and the leader board for most quakes
that sort of thing and that's what the
staff service is sort of there to do
as folks who may have worked on you know
a blockchain based network or even just
a database application may know um it's
helpful to have another service sort of
um reading information tallying
information you know putting together
those uh stats those metrics um for
users and in this case for the end user
application um so that will make sure
that you know unlike in other social
networks um you can verify that trends
are correct right the trend numbers are
the right trend numbers coming from this
service which is reading directly from
the block and that can obviously be
verified back and forth
it'll also make sure that the follower
numbers that you're getting when people
see your profile on a machine you know
on the other side of the world that
they're seeing you know the correct
follower following numbers and so on um
so that seems like a small piece but
it's actually kind of a big deal
and doing that push and pull and sort of
having that information flow through the
network is a really central piece to
making the application alive right
so i'm very excited about that and
we're we're gonna keep building on that
so um so yeah another piece you know
not completely done but uh getting very
very close so um
i think you'll see pieces of that within
the next week
thanks so much sean um i'm just
absolutely thrilled about our progress i
really don't even know how to describe
what a pleasure it is to see this all
coming together and i'm super excited
about the next steps because like i said
we're nearly at the end of the
application build and on the other side
of this is the steps to delivery it is
the network operations it is the system
that underpins that application and
makes it all work and from there we are
literally an end game we are in that
final phase heading towards delivery and
so
really now we just need to
have our amazing community who has got
us this far
carry us through
to that delivery the moment that we can
put this in your hands is going to be an
enormous celebration for many many
people not just in our team but
everybody who's ever been frustrated by
the way that they've been treated by big
tech by corporations by government
interests by security agencies by all of
the powerful people who've been meddling
in our abilities to maintain
relationships to build new relationships
and to have really important
conversations and to circulate really
important information that's what pain
quake is really doing it's putting the
power back in your hands to manage your
own relationships unimpeded and to
circulate information without
interference so
really help us guys you've got us this
far we've we've kept every promise to
you we really have kept all the promises
we made in the fourth and front of our
minds and it is now manifested in the
application
so
we're going to be talking a lot more
we're going to be releasing a lot more
we're going to be showing you a lot more
so that you can really see and get
excited about how close we now are to
being able to bring this to you thank
you so much for your support thank you
for your amazing emails and messages
thank you everyone who has helped to
this point and we will see you next
month with another delivery update and a
whole bunch more progress
see you
you